pharmaceuticalonline.com 2019-12-23

# Pharmaceutical Online: Privacy Statement

VertMarkets holds its readers and customers privacy in the highest regard. It is a core principle of our company. Because of this principle, Vertmarkets believes that you should fully understand the type of information we collect, how it is used and how you can control what information we collect. Therefore this privacy policy discloses what information we gather and how we use it.

**Information Collection and Use**  
VertMarkets collects information from our users at several different points on our web sites. Wherever we collect personal information, we include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. When you  **register**  with one of our sites or sign up to receive one of our newsletters and promotional emails, VertMarkets may ask for your contact information (such as your email address) and your demographic information (such as your zip code, industry, and job function). We use demographic information to tailor your experience at our web site, showing you content and advertisements that we think might interest you. VertMarkets may also ask for such information at other times, such as when you request information from VertMarkets and/or our customers and suppliers. The information collected by VertMarkets may be used in a number of ways. For example, VertMarkets will share broad aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. An example would be where VertMarkets provides partners and advertisers with information about the percentage ’C-Level’ individuals who visit our sites, or about the types of industries that users come from. VertMarkets' goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with the most personalized web experience possible and our advertisers with an efficient means to reach the right audience. By knowing a little about you, VertMarkets is able to deliver more relevant content and advertisements, and hence a better service, to you.

**With whom does VertMarkets share my information?**  
If you are requesting assistance, product information, white papers, case studies or brochures, your contact information may be shared with the developer of the relevant product, content, or software. Some materials that are available for download on VertMarkets' sites, like white papers, product demonstrations, case studies, and product literature, are offered in conjunction with a partner company. This information is shared with the partner company so that they may provide you with the material you requested. VertMarkets’ customer agreements with partner companies: (a) provide that the partner company may use this information in marketing related activities to contact you via common methods of communication; and (b) prohibit disclosure of the information to any third party other than agents of the Content Sponsor for the permitted marketing purposes set forth above; and (c) use of this contact information and adherence to the laws of any/all countries is the responsibility of the partner company.  You should contact the partner company directly if you have any questions about their use of this information.

In accordance with the GDPR no personally identifiable information from any EU member country individual will be shared unless affirmative and unambiguous consent to do so has been received. For more information on consent and the GDPR please visit our GDPR section in this privacy policy.

**Promotional offers**  
Any individual who signs up to receive one of our newsletters will be giving VertMarkets permission to send promotional offers for select VertMarkets’ products. Vertmarkets endeavors to promote to you products and services that are relevant and that we feel you would have a legitimate interest in hearing about. These products or services may include content newsletters, research reports, events and training seminars. You can opt out from receiving these promotions at any time by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of the offer email. 

In order to process these internal promotions VertMarkets may share your information, such as an email address with certain suppliers who are in contact with Vertmarkets. (i.e. an email service provider).

EU member country individuals please see additional information regarding consent in our GDPR section

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer by a web browser containing information associated with the user. We use cookies to be reminded of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register and helps VertMarkets make it easier for users when filling in the request information form.

If you do not want us to collect any initial cookies upon entering our site, you can set your browser to ‘private’ or ‘incognito’ mode.  Check with your browsers’ ‘help section’ for instructions.

Our website also uses Google Analytics Cookies.  Information collected by the Google Analytics cookies will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States of America in accordance with its privacy practices. To see an overview of privacy at Google and how this applies to Google Analytics, please [click here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html). You may opt out of tracking by Google Analytics by [clicking here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB).

If you do not want cookies on your browser from our site, follow the instructions below:

**How to control and delete cookies through the browser**

The ability to enable, disable or delete cookies can also be completed at browser level. In order to do this follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the “Help” section of your browser). 

Upon entering one of our sites, all users have the ability to accept our use of cookies. Full use of our website requires an individual to accept to use cookies while on our site.

**Third Party Cookies**  
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, a third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser that does not contain any information about the user.

**IP Addresses**  
We use IP addresses for purposes of system administration, and to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad firmographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Links**  
This web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that VertMarkets is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Site and Service Updates**  
We also send the user site and service announcement updates. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the user to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via email or phone.

**Notification of Changes;**   **Conflicts**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes here so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. This page reflects the most up-to-date version of our privacy policy, and thus takes precedence over information provided in P3P documents and other documents.

**Vertmarkets and the GDPR**

**What is the GDPR?**

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (Regulation (EU) 2016/679) is a regulation intended to strengthen and unify data protection for all individuals within the European Union (EU).  It also addresses the export of personal data outside the EU.  It aims primarily to give control back to citizens and residents over their personal data and to simplify the regulatory environment for international business by unifying the regulation within the EU.  It impacts any organization that processes personal data in connection with goods/services offered to an EU resident.   When the GDPR takes effect, it will replace the 1995 Data Protection Directive (Directive 95/46/EC).[2]    GDPR was adopted April 27, 2016 and becomes enforceable May 25, 2018.  To read more about the GDPR visit the official GDPR site.

**VertMarkets’ Commitment to Data Protection and GDPR Compliance**

As a 40+ year old Media Company, VertMarkets understands the importance of data security and the need to give our readers and our advertisers the ability to control and protect their personal data. 

We have carefully examined the relevant provisions of the GDPR, spoken to professional experts and are closely tracking any new applicable GDPR guidance.  These steps are helping us to ensure we will be compliant with all relevant provisions in the regulation by the May 25th 2018 enactment date. Some of the key elements of the GDPR that impact VertMarkets and its readers are:

**Consent**

In accordance with the GDPR VertMarkets will not share any personally identified information on an EU data subject with external third party partners, without:

  * Affirmative and unambiguous consent upon signing up to one of our products or services and
  * Affirmative and unambiguous consent to our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy

In order to withdraw your consent please click here and complete the form as instructed.

**Data Portability**

Another aspect of the GDPR is the right for each website registrant or newsletter subscriber to have the ability to receive details on what information we have collected on them. In order to request this detail please click here and complete the form.

**The right to be ‘Forgotten’/Erasure**

The GDPR also provides our website registrants and/or newsletter subscribers with the ‘right to be forgotten’ or in other words have their information erased from our database.

In order to request this ‘erasure’ please click here and complete the form.

**Legitimate Interest**

VertMarkets may share your information with a third party Email Service Provider (ESP) in order to promote VertMarkets’s products and service only, if VertMarkets believes you have a legitimate interest in receiving the offer.

**Contact**

Please contact us with any question regarding this policy by email at intellectualproperty@vertmarkets.com; by phone at 215-675-1800; or by mail at 101 Gibraltar Road, Suite 100, Horsham, PA 19044.

VertMarkets Privacy Policy, May 2018.
